Isabella Karle and Jerome Karle Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Jerome Karle Papers, 1912-2009 (Box 174-412)
  - Subject File, 1912-2009 (Box 318-412)
    The Subject File primarily documents Karle’s research activities and interests throughout his career, with an emphasis on his collaborative working relationships at the NRL. The largest group of files in the series are related to Steve Brenner, research chemist at NRL from 1962 to 2007, who collaborated with Karle on computer operations and calculations. The files contain crystallographic data printouts along with notes by Karle. Received in containers labeled “Steve Brenner apps,” the files were arranged chronologically in the order they were received. The folder dates were maintained in order to provide context, especially given their specificity. Researchers should be aware that the actual dates of materials within each folder may vary. A significant research file mostly from the 1950s and early 1960s was also maintained as received. These materials comprise notes, writings, equations, data, and likely relate to Karle’s collaboration with Herbert A. Hauptman on the topic of phase determination. Other significant collaborations in the subseries include Karle’s work with Lulu Huang and Lou Massa on the subject of quantum crystallography in the late 1990s and early 2000s. Specific topics throughout the subseries include anomalous dispersion, electron diffraction, various computational chemistry programs, and projects associated with the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency. The subseries also includes Karle’s recommendation letters and referee comments.
    Material types include reports, slides, clippings, notes, correspondence, writings, schedules, laboratory notebooks, articles, pamphlets, and photographs. Some textual materials are in digital formats.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject. The file structure of the digital content maintained as received.
    - 1,1-diamino-2,2-dinitroethylene (DADNE; FOX-7), 1998-1999 (Box 318)
    - 1,2-difluorodinitroethyline, 2000 (Box 318)
    - 1F₂,m b1z, 1978-1983 (Box 318)
    - "Advanced Bio-Chemical Technology Program" by I. Skurnick, 1983 (Box 319)
    - Akademii︠a︡ nauk SSSR, 1954-1960 (Box 319)
    - "African Eco-Technology Centre," Tunis, Tunisia, 1993-1994 (Box 319)
    - Algorithm for transforming coordinates, 1991-1993 (Box 319)
    - Amateur physics; Parapsychology; Conspiracy theories, 1975-1976, 1989-1992 (Box 319)
    - Amino acid structure factors and proteins, undated (Box 319)
    - Amorphous structure, theoretical manipulations, 1959, 1967, undated (Box 319)
    - Anamalous dispersion (Box 319)
      - Application, 1958, 1984-1992 (Box 319)
      - Isomorpheres replacement, 1980, 1999 (Box 319)
      - Miscellany, 1961, 1969, 1972-1989, (2 folders) (Box 320)
      - Slides, undated (Box 320)
      - Two systems, 1985-1988 (Box 320)
    - Anamalous scattering, 1967, undated (Box 320)
    - Antimalarial drugs, 1966 (Box 320)
    - Applications of group theory, undated (Box 320)
    - Argonne National Laboratory, 1988-1991, 2001-2003 (Box 320)
    - Atlantic Legal Foundation, Amici Curiae, "Frey Rule," 1992-1993 (Box 320)
    - Atom bomb, 1995-1996 (Box 320)
    - Atomic clocks, 1992 (Box 320)
    - Atomic scattering factors, 1928-1934, 1946-1950, 1957-1960 (Box 321)
    - B₃,₀, 1970-1974 (Box 321)
    - Bader, R. F. W., 1991-1993 (Box 321)
    - Bartlett, Rodney, 1999-2001 (Box 321)
    - Bessel functions, 1945, 1972 (Box 321)
    - "Bibliography of Gas Phase Electron Diffraction, 1930-1979," 1981 (Box 321)
    - BioSync, structural biology synchrotron users organization, 1989-1998 (Box 321)
    - Biguanidinium dinitramide, 1994 (Box 321)
    - Black hole, 1981-1982, undated See also Container 323, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 322)
    - Block functions for superconductivity, 1987-1988 (Box 322)
    - Bonham, Russell A., 1961 (Box 322)
    - Book orders, 1956-1958 (Box 322)
    - Boron, 1979-1980 (Box 322)
    - Braier, Nancy, computer programs, 2000 (Box 322)
    - Brayshaw, Paul, 1999-2000 (Box 322)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 322)
      - 1959-1999, Memoranda (Box 322)
      - 1961-1962, Miscellany (Box 322)
      - 1966-1987, Miscellaneous memoranda (Box 322)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 323)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 323)
        - Cosine invariants (Box 323)
        - Memoranda (Box 323)
        - Smoothing (Box 323)
      - 1973, Memoranda; Different least squares systems (Box 323)
      - 1975, Naval Research Laboratory network; Memoranda (Box 323)
      - 1976, Memoranda; Pentamine (Box 323)
      - 1977-1979, Miscellany (Box 323)
      - 1981, Black hole See also Container 323, same heading (Box 323)
      - 1981-1982, Memoranda, (2 folders) (Box 323)
      - 1982, Memoranda; Smoothing; Discontinuity (Box 323)
      - 1983, Memoranda; Anamolous dispersion (Box 323)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 324)
      - 1983, "The XTAL System of Crystallographic Programs: User's Manual" (Box 324)
      - 1983-1987, Memoranda (Box 324)
      - 1983-1992, Computation book (Box 324)
      - 1984 (Box 324)
        - Anomalous dispersion; Memoranda (Box 324)
        - Various least squares formulas (Box 324)
      - 1985, Apr., Program listing, ANALF2C550 (Box 324)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 325)
      - 1985, May 28, Listing (Box 325)
      - 1985, July-Aug., CLOSE.CRY (Box 325)
      - 1985, Aug. 13, LSQDIV4A.CRY (Box 325)
      - 1985, Aug. (Box 325)
        - LSQDIV2BB.CRY (Box 325)
        - LSQDIV2E.CRY (Box 325)
      - 1985, Oct., Tangent formula; URRY structure (Box 325)
      - 1985, Zero fourier map, (2 folders) (Box 325)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 326)
      - 1986, Apr., FFT.FOR (Box 326)
      - 1986, May 16, VECTSRCH13.CRY (Box 326)
      - 1986, Oct., SYMANTAM (Box 326)
      - 1986, "First part" and "second part", (2 folders) (Box 326)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 327)
      - 1986 (Box 327)
        - Frequency analysis (Box 327)
        - Miscellany (Box 327)
        - PPFOR (Box 327)
        - PPRAT, x-ray system (Box 327)
        - Zero fourier map (Box 327)
      - 1987, Mar., Linear LSQ (Box 327)
      - 1987, Mar.-Apr., Memoranda (Box 327)
      - 1987, July, LSQXYZLNF.CRY (Box 327)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 328)
      - 1987, Oct. 16, Program listing (Box 328)
      - 1987 (Box 328)
        - Memoranda (Box 328)
        - Memoranda; Power of two (Box 328)
      - 1988, Apr., Determinant (Box 328)
      - 1988, Oct., Arginine data (Box 328)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 329)
      - 1988, Oct., XRAY24.CRY; Arginine (Box 329)
      - 1988, Program listing (Box 329)
      - 1988, 1998-2000, Computation book (Box 329)
      - 1989, Least squares program, (2 folders) (Box 329)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 330)
      - 1989, Memoranda (Box 330)
      - circa 1989, Charney plot (Box 330)
      - 1990, Mar., LSQEXP1.CRY (Box 330)
      - 1990, Apr., Miscellany, (2 folders) (Box 330)
      - 1990, May, Program listing (Box 330)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 331)
      - 1990, June 5, Program listing, ELECTDSF.CRY (Box 331)
      - 1990, June 30, Symbolic procedure (Box 331)
      - 1990, July, Program listing (Box 331)
      - 1990, Sept., ZFIX30.CRY (Box 331)
      - 1990, Nov. (Box 331)
        - Miscellany, (2 folders) (Box 331)
        - Program listing (Box 331)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 332)
      - 1990, Memoranda, (2 folders) (Box 332)
      - 1991, Mar., LSQINVC50.CRY (Box 332)
      - 1991, Apr., LSQINVD.CRY (Box 332)
      - 1991, June 1, Programs for Lulu Huang and Lou Massa (Box 332)
      - 1991, July 11, P matrix (Box 332)
      - 1991, July, Starbase (Box 332)
      - 1991, Aug., Cosine invariants (Box 332)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 333)
      - 1991, Oct., Program listing; Functions (Box 333)
      - 1991, Nov. (Box 333)
        - Least squares (Box 333)
        - Miscellany (Box 333)
      - 1991, Memoranda (Box 333)
      - 1991-1993, Program listing (Box 333)
      - 1991-1994, Unix tips; Fortran development; Personal (Box 333)
      - 1992, Jan., SERADM; Sigma 2; 174 vectors (Box 333)
      - 1992, Mar. 30, PROG033092 (Box 333)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 334)
      - 1992, May, X-ray (Box 334)
      - 1992, June, Program listing, LSQRFF (Box 334)
      - 1992, Sept., P matrix (Box 334)
      - 1992, Nov., Memoranda; Huang, Lulu (Box 334)
      - 1992, Memoranda (Box 334)
      - 1993, Apr. 13, LSQINV.CRY; Cosine invariant (Box 334)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 335)
      - 1993, Apr., Cosine invariant (Box 335)
      - 1993, June 27, Invariant (Box 335)
      - 1993, June (Box 335)
        - Cosine invariant and phase compare (Box 335)
        - Huang, Lulu, email (Box 335)
        - Invariants and phase (Box 335)
        - LSQ82 (Box 335)
        - LSQIV (Box 335)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 336)
      - 1993, July 8, LSQINV.300 vector calculation (Box 336)
      - 1993, July 28, Memoranda and program listing (Box 336)
      - 1993, July, LSQINV1 and HWCM (Box 336)
      - 1993, Sept., Weighted LSQ (Box 336)
      - 1993, Sept.-Oct., Charney (Box 336)
      - 1993, Dec., Memoranda and program listing (Box 336)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 337)
      - 1993 (Box 337)
        - AXPAND.L (Box 337)
        - Memoranda (Box 337)
        - National Aeronautics and Space Administration Center for Computational Sciences (Box 337)
      - 1994, Jan., Memoranda and data (Box 337)
      - 1994, Jan.-Feb., Least squares and tangent formula (Box 337)
      - 1994, Feb. 24, Dec. 23, LSQAV, 1994, Dec. 23 (Box 337)
      - 1994, May 16, Dec., Memoranda, 1994, Dec. (Box 337)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 338)
      - 1994, June 13, Least squares to determinant (Box 338)
      - 1994, June (Box 338)
        - Memoranda and data (Box 338)
        - Program listing (Box 338)
      - 1994, July 15, Memoranda; Determinant (Box 338)
      - 1994, July, Program listing (Box 338)
      - 1994, Oct., Medusa; XTAL32 (Box 338)
      - 1994, Nov., Straight least squares (Box 338)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 339)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 339)
        - Memoranda (Box 339)
        - Memoranda; Determinant calculations (Box 339)
      - 1995, June, Least squares on phases; Memoranda (Box 339)
      - 1995, Oct., Program listing (Box 339)
      - 1995, Memoranda; Determinants (Box 339)
      - 1995-1996, Memoranda (Box 339)
      - 1996, May 13, AAMBLT (Box 339)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 340)
      - 1996, July 2-3, Arginine, (2 folders) (Box 340)
      - 1996, Aug. 6, Program listing; ALL.F (Box 340)
      - 1996, Aug. 30, Least squares on tangent formula (Box 340)
      - 1996, Oct. 29, Program listing (Box 340)
      - 1996, VECTOR.LOG (Box 340)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 341)
      - 1997, Jan. 15, Memoranda (Box 341)
      - 1997, Jan. 31, Five atoms calculation (Box 341)
      - 1997, Mar. 26, Five atoms (Box 341)
      - 1997, Apr., June 16, Program listing, 1997, June 16; (2 folders) (Box 341)
      - 1997, July 23, Plot and least square (Box 341)
      - 1997, Nov. 19, Type 3 calculation (Box 341)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 342)
      - 1997, Dec., Program listing (Box 342)
      - 1997 (Box 342)
        - Least squares on Gaussian (Box 342)
        - PPP; TCP (Box 342)
        - Program listing (Box 342)
      - 1997-1998 (Box 342)
        - Cambridge crystallographic database system (Box 342)
        - Memoranda (Box 342)
      - 1998, Mar., Occupancy calculation (Box 342)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 343)
      - 1998, Apr., Occupancy calculation (Box 343)
      - 1998, May, Program listing; Tangent formula (Box 343)
      - 1998, June 1, Program listing (Box 343)
      - 1998, June 15, Memoranda and data (Box 343)
      - 1998, July 13 (Box 343)
        - Program listing; Bond distance and angle (Box 343)
        - Plot on SGI (Box 343)
      - 1998, Aug., SER-ADM (Box 343)
      - 1998, Sept., Program listing; Memoranda (Box 343)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 344)
      - 1998, Sept., SER-ADM (Box 344)
      - 1998, Nov., Least squares calculations and symbolic addition (Box 344)
      - 1998-1999 (Box 344)
        - Memoranda (Box 344)
        - Tangent formula (Box 344)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 345)
      - 1999, Jan. (Box 345)
        - SER-ADM sigma 2 calculations, (2 folders) (Box 345)
        - SER-ADM tangent formula (Box 345)
      - 1999, Feb., ALL.F (Box 345)
      - 1999, Apr. 4, SER-ADM sigma 2 algorithm (Box 345)
      - 1999, June, Memoranda and data; Numerical phase (Box 345)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 346)
      - 1999, July-Aug. SER-ADM calculations, (2 folders) (Box 346)
      - 1999, Nov., 300 vectors, SER-ADM (Box 346)
      - 1999, Dec., SER-ADM (Box 346)
      - 1999-2006, Computation book (Box 346)
      - 2000, Jan. 21, Miscellany (Box 346)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 347)
      - 2000, Feb. 11, Tangent formula (Box 347)
      - 2000, Feb. 17, Miscellany (Box 347)
      - 2000, Feb., SER-ADM parts (Box 347)
      - 2000, Mar. 8, Tangent formula (Box 347)
      - 2000, Mar. 16, 276 vectors (Box 347)
      - 2000, Mar. 16 (Box 347)
        - Miscellany (Box 347)
        - SER-ADM, 2000, Apr. (Box 347)
      - 2000, May 16, Miscellany (Box 347)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 348)
      - 2000, May, Damping, rolling, SER-ADM (Box 348)
      - 2000, June 30, Miscellany (Box 348)
      - 2000, July 10, E least squares (Box 348)
      - 2000, July 14, Least squares (Box 348)
      - 2000, Aug. 24, Miscellany (Box 348)
      - 2000, Aug., Program listing (Box 348)
      - 2000, Aug.-Sept., Memoranda (Box 348)
      - 2000, Sept. 1-6, Least squares occupancy, (2 folders) (Box 348)
      - 2000, Sept. 8, Miscellany (Box 348)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 349)
      - 2000, Oct.-Dec., Memoranda (Box 349)
      - 2000, Nov. 12, Arginine (Box 349)
      - 2000, Nov. 19, Miscellany (Box 349)
      - 2001, Feb., Miscellany (Box 349)
      - 2001, Mar., Tetranitro cyclobutane (Box 349)
      - 2001, Apr. 3, Miscellany (Box 349)
      - 2001, Apr. 10, PHASEOCCUP.CRY (Box 349)
      - 2001, Apr.-May, Patterson (Box 349)
      - 2001, May-Aug., Miscellany, (2 folders) (Box 349)
      - 2001, Nov., Patterson occupancy (Box 349)
      - 2001, Dec., Patterson (Box 349)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 350)
      - 2001-2004, Memoranda, (2 folders) (Box 350)
      - 2002, Jan., Miscellany (Box 350)
      - 2002, Feb. 13, Intercept P2₁2₁2₁ (Box 350)
      - 2002, Feb. 22, Patterson (Box 350)
      - 2002, Feb. 22-May, Miscellany, (6 folders) (Box 350)
      - 2002, June 3-7, P2₁2₁2₁, (2 folders) (Box 350)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 351)
      - 2002, June 9, Miscellany (Box 351)
      - 2002, July, ALL 070102 (Box 351)
      - 2002, Sept., Program listing P2₁2₁2₁ (Box 351)
      - 2002, Oct. 18, ALL101802 (Box 351)
      - 2002-2004, Computing (Box 351)
      - 2003, Apr.-May, Miscellany (Box 351)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 352)
      - 2003, July 2, Ideal Patterson data (Box 352)
      - 2003, July 16-Aug. 5, P2₁2₁2₁ Patterson, (2 folders) (Box 352)
      - 2003, Aug. 28, Miscellany (Box 352)
      - 2003, Aug., SYMFIND (Box 352)
      - 2003, Sept. 3, Ideal data (Box 352)
      - 2003, Sept. 24, Fast fourier (Box 352)
      - 2003, Sept. (Box 352)
        - Fast fourier transform (Box 352)
        - Fourier and Patterson calculation listing (Box 352)
      - 2003, Oct. 17, Miscellany (Box 352)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 353)
      - 2003, Oct. 23, Ideal data (Box 353)
      - 2003, Oct., Miscellany (Box 353)
      - 2003, Nov. 17, Plugging (Box 353)
      - 2003, Nov. 25, Patterson (Box 353)
      - 2003, Dec.-2004, Feb., Find atoms (Box 353)
      - 2004, Jan.-Mar., No atoms (Box 353)
      - 2004, Apr. 28, N occupancy (Box 353)
      - 2004, June-Sept., Least squares occupancy, (2 folders) (Box 353)
      - 2004, Oct., Arginine; Patterson (Box 353)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 354)
      - 2004, Dec., Patterson 4 atoms calculation (Box 354)
      - 2004 (Box 354)
        - Directory (Box 354)
        - Fast fourier (Box 354)
        - Memoranda, (2 folders) (Box 354)
        - N occupancy (Box 354)
      - 2004-2005 (Box 354)
        - Fast fourier (Box 354)
        - RasMol (computer program); Miscellany (Box 354)
      - 2005, Jan., Miscellany (Box 354)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 355)
      - 2005, Mar.-Apr., Miscellany, (2 folders) (Box 355)
      - 2005, Apr., Program listing (Box 355)
      - 2005, May 4-11, Fourier, (2 folders) (Box 355)
      - 2005, May 15, Miscellany (Box 355)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 356)
      - 2005, May 17-31, Miscellany (Box 356)
      - 2005, June 2, Vector 66 (Box 356)
      - 2005, June 8, Vector 6 (Box 356)
      - 2005, June 15 (Box 356)
        - Vector 18 (Box 356)
        - Vector 56 (Box 356)
      - 2005, June 20, Vector 36 (Box 356)
      - 2005, June 23, Vectors 26, 50, and 52 (Box 356)
      - 2005, June 27, Best fit (Box 356)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 357)
      - 2005, June-July 5, Miscellaneous vectors, (2 folders) (Box 357)
      - 2005, July 11, Vector 100 (Box 357)
      - 2005, July 13, 56 atom (Box 357)
      - 2005, July 19, 56 atom, Patterson (Box 357)
      - 2005, July, Miscellany (Box 357)
      - 2005, Aug. 10, Ideal Patterson (Box 357)
      - 2005, Nov. 3, 5 atom problem, (2 folders) (Box 357)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 358)
      - 2005, Nov. 4, 12 atom problem (Box 358)
      - 2005, Nov. 31, 4 atom (Box 358)
      - 2005, Miscellany (Box 358)
      - 2006, Feb. 21-28, 12 atom, (2 folders) (Box 358)
      - 2006, May 31, Vector 5 (Box 358)
      - 2006, June 1, Vector 58 (Box 358)
      - 2006, June (Box 358)
        - Vector 6 (Box 358)
        - Vector 38 (Box 358)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 359)
      - 2006, July 19, 56 atom (Box 359)
      - 2006, Oct. 27-Nov., Patterson calculations, (2 folders) (Box 359)
      - 2006-2007, Miscellany, (2 folders) (Box 359)
    - Brenner, Steve (Box 360)
      - 2006-2007, Patterson, (2 folders) (Box 360)
      - 2007, Oct. 3, Final work (Box 360)
      - Undated (Box 360)
        - Calculations on chaperone function (Box 360)
        - Memoranda (Box 360)
        - Miscellany (Box 360)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory, Upton, N.Y. (Box 360)
      - Crystallographic Computing Network (CRYSNET), 1975 (Box 360)
      - National Synchrotron Light Source, 1976-1977 (Box 360)
      - National Synchrotron Light Source, 1979-2004, (2 folders) (Box 361)
    - Bukowski, Robert, Szalewicz, Krysztof, 1997-2001 (Box 361)
    - C₃F₆, 1948-1950, 1966-1969, undated (Box 361)
    - Calculations, miscellaneous, 1973, undated (Box OV 5)
    - Calibration masks, 1974 (Box 361)
    - Calmodulin, 1984-1985 (Box 361)
    - Cancer, 1976-1981 (Box 361)
    - CASTEP (computer program); National Center for Supercomputing, 2000 (Box 361)
    - Chaos, 1985, 1992-1994, (2 folders) (Box 361)
    - CHEETAH (computer program), 2002, undated (Box 361)
    - Cho, Y. S., 1995-2001, (5 folders) (Box 362)
    - Cho, Y. S., 2002-2004 (Box 363)
    - Clathrates, 1987-1991 (Box 363)
    - Clippings, 1961-1965 (Box 363)
    - CNS (computer program); Brunger, Axel, 2000 (Box 363)
    - Cold fusion, 1989-1992 (Box 363)
    - Colemanite, 1953-1954 (Box 363)
    - Collela, Roberto, 1972, 1987 (Box 363)
    - Computational chemistry and materials science, 1999 (Box 363)
    - Computing, density functional methods, 1997-2000 (Box 363)
    - Conjugate gradient program; Konnert, John, 1998 (Box 363)
    - Containers for condensors, undated (Box 363)
    - Contours and general computer programs, 1998 (Box 363)
    - Correlation problem; McWeeny R., 1976, 1997-2000 (Box 363)
    - Cosine invariant problem, 1982, 1991-1993 (Box 363)
    - "Critical Points in Three Dimensions" by Herbert B. Rosenstock, undated (Box 363)
    - Crystal 95 1997, mss85507_215_015; mss85507_215_016
    - Crystal 95; Crystal 98, 1995-1999, (2 folders) (Box 363)
    - Crystal 98 1999, mss85507_215_017
    - Crystallographic data, 1975, 1987-1993 (Box 364)
    - C₃F₆, 1963-1972, undated, (6 folders) (Box 364)
    - Cubane, 1995-1998 (Box 364)
    - Cubane; Crystal 98 (computer program), 1990-2000 (Box 365)
    - "Current theoretical interest," 1977-1982, 1989-1990 (Box 365)
    - Cyvin, undated (Box 365)
    - Dardik, Irving, 1989-1990 (Box 365)
    - Debaerdemaeker, T.; Tate, C.; Woolfson, Michael Mark, 1965-1988 (Box 365)
    - Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, High Energy Density Matter program (Box 365)
      - Meetings, 1998, May-Aug., (3 folders) (Box 365)
      - Meetings, 1999, Jan.-2001, Aug., (6 folders) (Box 366)
      - Miscellany, 1999-2004 (Box 367)
      - N compound literature, 1968, 1999 (Box 367)
      - N₄ and N₈, 1964, 1994-1999 (Box 367)
      - Statement of work, 2000 (Box 367)
    - De Groot, H. J. M., 1990-1992 (Box 367)
    - Determinants, slides, 1979, undated (Box 367)
    - Development and Testing of New Approaches to Protein Structure Analysis (grant), 1997-2000, (2 folders) (Box 367)
    - Diaminodinitroethylene, 1998 (Box 367)
    - Dinitrocubane, 1996-1997 (Box 367)
    - "Direct Methods: Crossroad in New Methods" symposium, 1986-1987 (Box 367)
    - Direct phase determination, Chinese articles, 1980-1983 (Box 367)
    - "Discovery of Polonium and Radium- its Scientific and Philosophical Consequences, Benefits and Threats to Mankind," Warsaw, Poland, 1998, Sept. 17-20 (Box 368)
    - Distances and positions, 1950, undated (Box 368)
    - d orbitals, 1973-1980, 1997 (Box 368)
    - Double rotors, 1945-1972, undated (Box 368)
    - Drug testing, hair, 1992-1998 (Box 368)
    - Dynamical theory, 1954-1962, 1977-1985 (Box 368)
    - Effect of symmetry on P matrix, 1996 (Box 368)
    - Electron density cross correlation with its square, 1996-1997 (Box 368)
    - Electron diffraction camera photographs, undated (Box 368)
    - Electron diffraction; Electron excitation, undated (Box 368)
    - Electron diffraction, slides, undated See also Container OV 2, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 368)
    - "Electron Diffraction Study of Steel Panels Used in Bonderizing Tests," 1945 (Box 369)
    - Electron and relativity problem, 1936, 1958 (Box 369)
    - "Electron Scattering from an Unsymmetrical Charge Distribution by the First Born Approximation," 1958-1960 (Box 369)
    - Electron and Structural Properties of Amorphous Material (proposal), 1975 (Box 369)
    - Emil Greiner Company, 1946, 1959-1960 (Box 369)
    - Energetic materials workshop, 1996-1998 (Box 369)
    - "An Essentially Linear Approach to Phase Determination from Triplet Invariants," undated (Box 369)
    - Excited states, undated (Box 369)
    - Expected value evaluations of determinants, 1992 (Box 369)
    - Experimental triplet phase determination, 1964-1983 (Box 369)
    - Extended x-ray absorption fine structure, 1949-1950, 1974-1981 (Box 369)
    - Extension, 1974-1981 (Box 369)
    - Feldmann slides, identification, 1982-1986 (Box 369)
    - Fibrous structures, 1974, undated (Box 369)
    - Figures and illustrations, 1988-2005 (Box 369)
    - Figures and illustrations, 1994, undated See also Container OV 2, same heading, (5 folders) (Box 370)
    - Fivefold symmetry, 1984-1990 (Box 370)
    - Force fields between atoms ("energetic materials option"), 1981, undated (Box 370)
    - Fort, Deborah C., "Science Clubs and Competitions in the Youth of 1,500 Established U.S. Scientists, Technologists, Engineers, and Science Teachers," 1990-1991 (Box 370)
    - Fourier inversion, 1952-1953, 1985-1986 (Box 370)
    - Frauenfelder, Hans, 1980, 1989-1990 (Box 370)
    - Gaussian 88 (computer program); Gaussian 90 (computer program), 1990 (Box 371)
    - Gaussian 92 (computer program), 1993-1994 (Box 371)
    - Gaussian 94 (computer program), 1995-1998 (Box 371)
    - Gaussian 98 (computer program), 1998-2000 (Box 371)
    - Gaussian 98 (computer program); Small Business Innovation Research program, 1996-1998 (Box 371)
    - Gaussian functions for fitting Slater orbitals, 1973, 1985-1993 (Box 371)
    - Gavezzotti, Angelo, 1991-1998, (2 folders) (Box 371)
    - Gavezzotti, Angelo; PROMET (computer program), 1993-2000 (Box 371)